

Ganesh Kshirsagar

Linux/Cloud

Highly proficient with managing server infrastructure operation across multiple platforms (UNIX, Linux, Windows). Expert level knowledge of AWS EC2,S3,ELB,VPC,simple DB,RDS,SQS and other AWS services in the Cloud infrastructure such as LAAS,PAAS and SAAS. Hands on experience in development of utilities using shell scripting to automate process. Strong perseverance and diligence towards attaining challenging goals and possess good communication skills and quick learning ability.

TECHNCIAL EXPERIENCE

Red hat Server, Windows Server 08,12, AWS (Cloud Watch/ Cloud Front/ Elastic Beanstalk), Cloud Technologies, Java, shell Script's, Red hat, Ubuntu, Cent OS, SUSE Linux, Open SSH, Apache Tomcat, Chef, Puppet, Rack space cloud, Atlassian tools, Confluence, Jira ticketing tools, Nagios, Version control, GIT, SVN,ITIL Knowledge.

FREELANCE PROJECTS

Project #1 Cloud project (Hooper) Dates (Jan 2018 - April 2018)

Cloud project named as Hooper throughout using SAAS,IAAS,PAAS, containers, performance with X11 with SSH protocol.

Cloud migration project for application migration with 6 strategies as follows :- a) Rehosting, b) Platforming, C) Repurchasing, d) re-Archtecting, e) Retire, f) Retain.

Project #2 Cloud Migration project Dates(Dec 2018 - June 2019)

Used 3 strategies

Besides primary migration (Here are the three main cloud migration strategies businesses use to meet those goals.) :- a) Strategy #1: Homogeneous "Lift-and-Shift" Migration, b) Strategy #2: Technical Migration, c) Strategy #3: Application Migration.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SATech, Maharashtra, Pune Linux System Engineer 04/2017 to 07/2017

Troubleshoot and resolve Linux/Windows/Network/VMware/Application related problems at level 3 support worldwide as part of a 24/7 operational team. In an environment with Maps and AWS services

DevOps Role:

- Worked with Web Services like REST API & SOAP UI.
- Monitoring entire infrastructure with Nagios and ELK for logs and API.
- Managing and releasing scripts from Linux LAMP Environment for all infrastructures.
- Worked with Business teams to lead IT operations in growing products.
- Performing Technical research with team and independently.

Scalable Consulting and solution, Maharashtra, Pune Linux cloud consultant

01/2017 to 04/2017

AZURE ROLE:

- Designed and configured Azure Virtual Networks (VNets), subnets, Azure network settings, DHCP address blocks,
 DNS settings, and security policies and routing.
- Deployed Azure laaS virtual machines (VMs) and Cloud services (PaaS role instances) into secure VNets and subnets.

- Provided high availability for laaS VMs and PaaS role instances for access from other services in the VNet with Azure Internal Load Balancer.
- Led DevOps development of PowerShell command scripts, custom PowerShell C# cmdlets, Ansible, Puppet and Chef to configure, verify and monitor: networks, security, routes, IP-Forwarding, VMs and cloud service roles.

Azure POCs

- Reviewed, analyzed, and created prototype C# code to verify functionality of the following Azure services as proof of concepts (POCs) for:
- Data & Storage: SQL Database, Document DB, Storage (Blobs, Tables, Queues, Files and Disks)
- Led implementation of Office 365 and Azure Active Directory for single sign on, authentication, authorization and Azure Role-based Access Control (RBAC).

Implemented a structured design process for creating a hybrid cloud architectures to include on-premise resources, networks, security, IaaS, PaaS, SaaS architectures. Leading the architects to iterate through design steps and tasks to identify dependencies and resolving design conflicts where a design decision made in a later step may conflict with a design decision made in an earlier step, repeating the process until all considerations are incorporated into the final architecture design.

Trans perfect, Pune, Maharashtra

04/2016 to 012/2016

Linux Cloud system Operation Engineer

- Collaborated with developers to implement changes to websites on a development, test, and production servers.
- Provided coordination support between networks, Enterprise Applications and the development architecture.
- Systems support, maintenance an package management of 75 servers and 4 SANS
- Architecture design and support enterprise VMware environment for multiple US and International offices.
- Install and maintain Apache Tomcat Server, MySQL and Oracle Database servers
- Maintain and support enterprise NetApp Storage Filer.
- Replaced non-functioning Red-Hat Kick start server, allowing servers to be built at remote sites to accommodate customer requests during company's peak sales season.
- Set up test network modeling site's production network, allowing group's development software to be thoroughly tested prior to being deployed into production.

CMC Ltd, Pune, Maharashtra

04/2014 to 10/2015

System Engineer

- Served as the Tier-2 point of contact for researching, diagnosing, documenting and resolving server, network, database and work station issues
- Interacted with vendors to manage licensing/maintenance agreements and resolve hardware/software issues
- Ensured network and IP connectivity established uptime service level agreements of all application servers, and back-end infrastructure
- Engineered, designed, developed, and implemented computer networks, cyber-security infrastructure, information technology systems and tools

Expert infotech, Maharashtra, Pune System Administrator

01/2014 to 04/2014

Maintained and updated any needed system procedures and documentations

- Designed and implemented security policies for file servers, backup servers and system workstations
- Maintained MS Exchange Server Performed troubleshooting and provided resolutions for server problems.
- Administered combined Red hat Enterprise Linux and Windows Active Directory domain consisting of forty servers.
- Performed scheduled maintenance, security updates, and routine monitoring of TSA Enterprise Clustered Windows 2000 & 2003 Servers

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATION / OTHERS

Bachelor of Computer Science (B.C.S IT),Vivekanand College, Aurangabad (MH), India (2010). Certified in MCITP 2008, RHCE 6.0 Certified in Cloud DevOps